<resources>
    <string name="app_name">TourGuideApp</string>
    <string name="tab_monument">Monument</string>
    <string name="tab_hotel">Hotel</string>
    <string name="tab_night">Night</string>
    <string name="tab_shopping">Shopping</string>


    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="desc_img_image">image</string>

    <!--   MONUMENTS  -->
    <string-array name="monument_names_array">
        <item>Palais du Luxembourg</item>
        <item>Centre Pompidou</item>
        <item>Les Invalides</item>
        <item>Opéra Garnier</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="monument_description_array">
        <item>The Luxembourg Palace, surrounded by its beautiful gardens, was built in 1617.
            It owes its name to the Duke of Piney-Luxembourg, landlord of a domain which was
            later acquired by Maria de Medici,
            widow of the King of France, Henri IV. \n
            The Italian-born Queen wished to create a residence to remind her of the Pitti
            Palace as well as
            establishing gardens evoking those of Boboli in Florence. \n\n
            Architect Salomon de la Brosse was entrusted the construction of the palace.
            It now houses the French Senate, the upper house of Parliament.
            The palace opens onto a beautiful park, actually one of my favourites in Paris.
            I love coming here in Spring and in Autumn.
            If you have kids it also has a brilliant play area.</item>
        <item>The Pompidou Centre in the district of Beaubourg is one of France’s most visited museums.
            Not far from the busy shopping precinct of Les Halles,
            the Pompidou centre was designed in the style of high-tech architecture.
            With its colour-coded pipes and ducts, the design of the modern art museum has
            been the source of much controversy since its construction. \n\n
            Inaugurated in 1977, some see it as an eyesore, others praise its architectural audacity.
            Honestly I don’t really know what to think of it, that’s why I much prefer to climb on
            the top floor to enjoy the panoramic views over the roofs of Paris where it also
            has a famous restaurant.</item>
        <item>Now this is a place I’m much more familiar with as I used to work as a
            French teacher in a nearby language school. \n\n
            The grand complex of Les Invalides on the Left Bank is easily recognisable by
            its magnificent golden dome reaching 107 metres high. It was built by Louis XIV to
            house the homeless and wounded veterans of the King’s army. \n\n
            Today the Hôtel des Invalides is famous for housing the tomb of French emperor
            Napoleon Bonaparte. The Hôtel des Invalides also hosts three museums: the Army museum,
            the Order of the Liberation museum, and the Relief map museum.</item>
        <item>Charles Garnier built the opulent Paris Opera house from 1861 to 1875 during the
            reign of Napoleon III. It is part of the great reconstruction of Paris by Baron
            Haussmann during the Second Empire. \n\n
            The auditorium seats nearly 2,000 people and features a grand chandelier and a
            fine ceiling painting by Marc Chagall. You have to visit the interior of the opera house,
            including the astonishing great staircase. \n\n
            At certain times of the day you can pay to look around or have a guided tour.
            It’s just mind-blowing! You can sometimes get last minute tickets for operas and ballets
            but it is best to book in advance which you can do online.</item>
    </string-array>

    <!--  END MONUMENTS   -->

    <!--   SHOPPING   -->
    <string-array name="shopping_names_array">
        <item>Hermès</item>
        <item>Guerlain</item>
        <item>Galeries Lafayette Champs-Elysées</item>
        <item>Louis Vuitton Maison Champs-Élysées</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="shopping_description_array">
        <item>naugurated in 2018, the Hermès flagship in the Golden Triangle was renovated with
            great detail over two years. The shop now spans three levels and has 5,900 square feet
            of retail space. But what makes this particular location special are the wood-paneled
            façade and the gilded lettering on its unmistakable sign—both now beautifully restored.
            Inside, the design mixes airy and contemporary touches (gray-blue marble, mosaic floors)
            with traditional details and, of course, the brand\'s signature orange.</item>
        <item>No Guerlain store has the history of the perfumer\'s iconic outpost on the Champs-Elysées.
            The interior was revamped by architect Peter Marino five years ago, and today it features
            an array of Guerlain motifs, from golden Napoleonic bees to the Louis XIV sunburst emblem
            that has long adorned face powder compacts. Philippe Starck chandeliers offset mirrored
            ceilings and deep golden and mahogany tones in one room, while resin-coated table collages
            by Peter Dayton offer a splash of color in the café. The shop is worth a visit as much
            for the collection of products as for the show-stopping design.</item>
        <item>Family-owned retailer Galeries Lafayette reclaimed an Art Deco landmark (formerly the
            Virgin Megastore) on the Champs-Elysées and transformed it into a concept flagship with
            the help of Danish architect Bjarke Ingels. In a space spanning nearly 70,000 square feet
            and four floors, the shop eschews the usual boundaries in the retail experience, mixing
            goods from multiple categories for men and women rather than partitioning things into
            dedicated corners. The experience is meant to be fluid, encouraging shoppers to weave
            seamlessly from fashion to food to accessories.</item>
        <item>For die-hard Louis Vuitton fans (and fans of luxury more generally), there\'s no outpost
            more symbolic or prestigious than the brand\'s impressive perch on the well-heeled corner
            of the Champs-Elysées and the avenue George V. The largest Louis Vuitton location in the
            world, the five-floor store occupies a listed Art Deco building with a period dome visible
            from both ends of the avenue. You\'ll find everything from traditional leather goods, handbags
            and ready-to-wear, to homewares, jewelry, and even art books.</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--  END SHOPPING   -->

    <!--   HOTEL   -->
    <string-array name="hotel_names_array">
        <item>Hôtel Belles Rives</item>
        <item>La Coorniche</item>
        <item>Hotel Byblos</item>
        <item>Hotel du Palais</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="hotel_description_array">
        <item>La belle France is as much about where you stay as what you eat and do.
            Hotels in this ravishingly varied land of hilltop villages, alpine peaks,
            cosmopolitan cities and vineyard-stitched countryside are hopelessly enchanting –
            and never more so than in summer when that chic lifestyle which the French do
            so enviably well moves outside. \n\n
            Think luxurious treehouses in the rural Dordogne,
            design-hot villas on the Atlantic and Med seashores, historic chateaux with
            romantic dining beneath the stars, ancient riverside mills and urban hotels with
            rooftop bars – a collection of sublime summertime properties that have been rated
            and reviewed by Telegraph Travel’s France experts.</item>
        <item>This ravishing boutique getaway is the height of seaside sophistication. Philippe
            Starck’s bold white interior evokes local oyster farming, and Europe’s highest sand
            dune looms large as next-door neighbour. Outstanding seafood dining and sea-and-sand
            views at every turn are the icing on the cake. This hotel has story. It languishes in a
            traditional Basque, 1930s hunting lodge that gazes dreamily out onto the big blue seas
            of the Atlantic Ocean. The public beach is a short walk – if you can drag yourself away
            from the impossibly stylish infinity pool with cushioned sun loungers and incredible sea
            views that is. Staff can arrange boat taxis, seafaring picnics, visits to local oyster
            farms, bike rental and all sorts.</item>
        <item>Since 1967, the Byblos has come on like the Med\'s poshest sea-side village.
            A series of what look like fisherman\'s houses - all ochre and harmonious -
            unwind round the pool, and are themselves inundated with Med greenery. the hotel\'s
            focus of attention is the heated outdoor pool. Somewhere nearby is France\'s first Sisley
            spa, whose Salon Libanais - all 17th-century wooden marquetry and wondrously carved panels -
            hosted at least part of Mick and Bianca\'s wedding night. You\'ll maybe need it after a
            night in the Caves-du-Roy, France\'s most celeb-filled night-club. The nearest beaches
            are a 10-minute walk, the more famous Pampelonne stretch 15 minutes by car.</item>
        <item>@drawable/hotel_du_palais</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--  END HOTEL   -->

    <!--   NIGHT   -->
    <string-array name="night_names_array">
        <item>Les berges de Seine</item>
        <item>Quai Saint-Bernard</item>
        <item>Bassin de la Villette</item>
        <item>Les Bateaux Mouches</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="night_description_array">
        <item>Les berges de Seine is a new Parisian project that has transformed an old waterfront
            of the left (south) bank of the Seine river. \n\n
            The new area, starting at the Alma bridge, is a place to chill out,
            exercise as well to eat and drink. \n\n
            It goes up to the Solférino bridge that connects the left bank with famous Tuilleries Gardens.
            During the night, Les berges de Seine waterfront offers a view to the golden-shining
            Eiffel Tower, the famous Louvre and Orsay Museums and the art nouveau building
            called Grand Palais.
            Also, there are good restaurants and bars, where the night visitor can grab a
            drink while enjoying the reflection of lights in the Seine river.

</item>
        <item>Another popular waterfront is called Quai Saint-Bernard.
            It starts just behind the famous Notre-Dame Cathedral and is one of the more
            popular places for picnics.During summer nights, Quai Saint-Bernard is full of young
            people having fun while enjoying the night view to the Island of Saint Louis – the oldest
            part of Paris.
            In addition, during the month of July, Quai Saint-Bernard hosts a special dance festival.
            Each evening, three dance styles are presented in the rounded concrete area next to the river.
            And, the participation is free.
            So, what about an Argentinian tango class, entertaining Irish dance, or seductive salsa?
            Grab a beer and dive into the night dance fever!</item>
        <item>North of Paris, you can find a water canal with a small port that is called Bassin
            de la Villette.
            Both of its waterfronts are popular meeting points for young, artistic people.
            They are playing music, singing, and drinking.
            In addition, the port is full of cultural attractions –  a pair of artistic cinemas
            called MK2 offer a large scale of interesting movies to see.
            You’ll see numerous boats bars, anchoring each summer in the canal, watching various
            entertaining concerts and shows.</item>
        <item>An alternative to the night spent by enjoying riverfront attractions is 
            to try some of the Parisian Cruise tours.
            There are two main cruise lines, Bateaux Mouches and Les Vedettes du pont Neuf.
            Both offer tours around the main monuments, accompanied by a detailed information.</item>
    </string-array>
    <!--  END NIGHT   -->

</resources>
